<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-05-06T11:15:51+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Mauricio Cardona Jaramillo</title><subtitle>Welcome to my blog</subtitle><author><name>Mauricio Cardona Jaramillo</name></author><entry><title type="html">Handy guideline to buy a computer for non-experts</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/05/05/handy-guideline-to-buy-a-computer.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Handy guideline to buy a computer for non-experts" /><published>2021-05-05T21:55:52+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-05T21:55:52+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/05/05/handy-guideline-to-buy-a-computer</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/05/05/handy-guideline-to-buy-a-computer.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/imgs/buying%20a%20computer.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; title=&quot;Buying a computer&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to buying a computer and you step in the huge amount of options out there, it seems like a very difficult thing to do, and indeed it is. Even for experts it is a pain to make a wise choice. However, in this article, I will give you a little bit of context on the main components that need to be seen and narrow those option based on your needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was a teenager I used to hear people using the term ‘CPU’ to refer to the whole tower for desktop computers, and rapidly adopted the same term when talking about a PC. It was just until I got into college that I realised that CPU stands for Central Processing Unit and that this is the main component of the computer, not because the others are not important but because without a CPU your device is useless(or can be used for other purposes out of the scope of this article).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, the first component to study is the CPU or processor. There are two major manufacturers of computer processors, Intel® and AMD®. Each of them has 3 types of processors: Budget, mid-range or mainstream and high-end, being budget the cheapest of the three. At the end of this article, I will post some links you can use to compare processors and other resources you can use to have a look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second component to have a look at is the RAM which stands for Random Access Memory. It is a volatile memory(meaning that it is only available when your laptop is running, as soon as you shut it down it’s cleaned up). This memory is important because is the one that manages all the applications and processes your computer is running while you are using it. Your computer needs memory to open your Browser, Powerpoint, Spotify and so on; so, when you open each of them the responsible to handle all the stuff underneath is the RAM. In the market you can find RAMs up to 32Gb and gamers usually make it up to 64 or even more. For us, starting from 4Gb until 16Gb is enough. Now that you know what is it for, if you usually use your computer for browsing the Internet and writing some docs a 4Gb RAM is a good choice, personally would recommend going straight to 8Gb since the price doesn’t increase here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the storage. There are two types of this one. HDD or Hard Drive Disk and SDD or Solid-State drive. The main difference between the two: SSD is way faster than HDD. As its name says, HDD uses a disk to read and write information whereas SSD doesn’t. 2021 laptops and computers come with SSD but if you are after a second-hand device you should probably have a look a this before buying. There is one more that is becoming more popular call NVMe and stands for Non-volatile Memory Express and is way faster than SSD. So if you are buying and you see the storage is NVMe and it fits your budget, go for it, if not, then go for SSD. HDD is not an option anymore for today’s computers. Try to find an SSD that suits your budget.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Mauricio Cardona Jaramillo</name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>